# Melbourne A. Mijan CCNA.CCENT.MCTS.MCP.Network +

209972332187/ 09458459180≥ bournemjn@gmail.com219 Pagkasilasa Drive. Talon-Talon Z.C



Objective:

### **IT Support Technician**

### Summary of Skills

Seeking a position where more than 14 years of experience and will contribute to increase efficiency, an energetic team-player able to motivate staff for best results. Due to my strong background and achievement in successfully identifying gaps and creating efficiencies.

### Work Experience

### **Recently Working in**

Ateneo de Zamboanga University. As IT Tech Support La Purisima Street Zamboanga City. From Sept. 12, 2019 July 30, 2020.

### **Previous Work:**

## Network Technical Support Ministry of Interior

Doha, State of Qatar Dec 2012 to Dec 2017 Finish Contract Last Dec 2,2017.

### **Recently Working in**

Southern City Colleges Pilar St. Zamboanga City Aug – Dec 2018.

**SBG-PBAD (Riyadh K.S.A)**2008-2011. AutoCAD (MEP. Electrical)

### **Baud Telecom Company**

Telecom Technician (Riyadh K.S.A) 2006-2008

#### **Duties and Responsibilities:**

Computer Technician, Network Troubleshooting, CCTV, attending client Network and Desktop/Printer Trouble Shooting. Desktop formatting, Anti-virus ESET installation, and Attending Seminar and Universities extra curricular activities.

#### **Duties and Responsibilities:**

Network Technical Support, Cisco Router & Cisco Switch, Computer Trouble shooting, CCTV Installation IP Camera, Troubleshooting. Network Printer HP500 m551, Scanner, Structured Cabling, visiting remote site and IP Phone Telephony as well.

Diagnose problems with hardware (PC desktop or Server).

### **Duties and Responsibilities:**

Educating Junior high School student on how to Use basic computer. Application, such as Microsoft office. MS-word, Excel, Power Point, Access and some other application.

#### **Duties and Responsibilities:**

Responsible for Shop Drawing for Electrical Low Current and Power, and Lighting.

Coordination to the other discipline like Mechanical, Architectural, Civil and Plumbing.

### **Duties and Responsibilities:**

- •Perform duties as Outside Technician, Installation and Implementation, Configuration, Wi-fi and wireless network.
- Conduct site survey, Project implementation. With a minimum supervision.
- Hardware Installation (Cisco Router 7600 Provider Edge (PE), Cisco Catalyst Switch7690, Zhone (MALC) (SAUDI TELECOM

bournemjn@gmail.com

# Melbourne A. Mijan CCNA, CCENT, MCTS, MCP, Network +

209972332187/ 09458459180
 ⇒bournemjn@gmail.com
 219 Pagkasilasa Drive. Talon-Talon Z.C

IBCOL Technical Services GMBH Electronics Technician Riyadh K.S.A 1999-2003`

### Duties and Responsibilities

- Responsible for the installation of CCTV and Security System
- Installation of Road Blocker and tire Killer
- Installation of CCTV and Remote System
- Prepare daily safety reports base on site condition and development
- Responsible for Remote Camera System Repair and Installation
- Security HI-SCANNER
- System Communication using Windows NT 4 Server
- Using AutoCAD for layout ting Electrical Drawings and Electronics Spare parts
- Inventory of Electrical Equipment, tools Material supply using Excel.

## **Education / Training**

## Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering

Universidad de Zamboanga Zamboanga City, Philippines Graduate: March 1998.

# MICROCADD SM MANILA AUTHORIZED TRAINING CENTER

TRAINING DURATION 75 HRS. Feb 12 to 23 2018

Computer Engineers applying algorithmic and digital design principles to design, build, and test computer software or hardware components used for information Network &communication, and storage – typically embedded in large engineered systems distributed.

AutoCAD 2018 w /Fusion 360 2D,3D Rendering Plot. Autodesk Certificate No.1FSXRUXFS5.

Be able to drafts 2D&3D Architectural Drawing, Rendering and Plotting. Microsoft Office Word, Excel, Access, Power point and Outlook. Basic Linux operation.

bournemjn@gmail.com

# Melbourne A. Mijan

CCNA,CCENT,MCTS,MCP,Network +

**2**09972332187/09458459180

⊠bournemjn@gmail.com

219 Pagkasilasa Drive. Talon-Talon Z.C

### Cisco Certified Entry Network Technician

Cisco ID No. CSCO11733887 Cisco Networking Academy Program Education and Training, Riyadh, K.S.A.

Completed: February 2010



## Cisco Certified Network Associate

Cisco ID No. CSCO11733887 Riyadh, K.S.A.

Completed: February 2010



## Microsoft Certified Technology Specialist

Microsoft ID No. 7400934 Riyadh, K.S.A.

Completed: March 2010.



- Be able to identify and describe IP Address Classes.
- Proficient in using the binary number system.
- Proficient in IP address subnetting techniques.
- Be able to describe the purpose of the OSI Model and functions of each layer.
- Be able to described the process of data encapsulation
- Be able to make a patch cable.

Routing and Switching Configuration using Routing protocol. RIPv2, EIGRP, OSPF. ASA Firewall. Cisco Prime Infrastructure.

- Install components; analyze problems; diagnose and repair systems.
- Diagnose problems with hardware (PC desktop or server).
- Repair or upgrade hardware.
- Compute and use Variable Length Subnet Masking (VLSM) techniques to design and implement effective and efficient IP addressing.
- Configure and use the RIPv2 distance vector routing protocol, EIGRP, OSPF.
- Describe the concepts and techniques of link-state routing and compare and contrast with distance vector routing.
- Configure and use the Open Shortest Path First (OSPF) linkstate routing protocol in a single area mode of operation
- Configure and use the Extended IGRP (EIGRP) routing protocol. Switching Configuration VTP, STP, DTP, VLAN. IP MPLS. Cisco Prime Infrastructure, ASA Firewall.
- Maintain local MS servers and small network with Cisco firewall.
- •Perform pro-active maintenance on all Computer networks. Oversee technician and consultant as needed.
- Installing Windows 7 Professional, Windows 7 Ulltimate. Windows Server 2008 r2 2012
- Implementing and Conductin gAdministration of resources.
- •Implementing, Managing, Monitoring, and Troubleshooting. Windows Server 2008 r2, 2012.
  Configuring DHCP Server, Web Server, Client Server
  Print Server. Network Trouble Shooting, Microsoft Exchange Server 2008 & 2010. Group Policy, DNS Server.
- Be on call to support essential business clients and emergency situations.
- Provide support for Servers and infrastructure application users, including upgrades, installation, troubleshooting and maintenance. Support the systems administration activities.

# Melbourne A. Mijan CCNA, CCENT, MCTS, MCP, Network +

**2**09972332187/ 09458459180 □ bournemjn@gmail.com

□ 219 Pagkasilasa Drive. Talon-Talon Z.C

# Microsoft Certified Professional (MCP) Microsoft ID No. 7400934

Riyadh, K.S.A.

Completed: April 2010.



- Installing Windows 7 Ultimate, Professional
- •Implementing and Conducting Administration of Resources
- •Implementing, Managing, Monitoring, and Troubleshooting. Network printer setup and configuration. Microsoft Office 2010 & 2016.
- Provide support for All non-core Servers and Infrastructure Applications (Active Directory, Exchange, Archiving, Enterprise Backup, Share point, etc.), including upgrades, installation, troubleshooting and maintenance.

### ComTIA Network+ Certified Network+ ID No. COMP001020083468

ComTIA Network Plus Certified (Network+) Riyadh, K.S.A. Completed: March 2010.



- Recongnize the following Logical or Physical Network given in a diagram, schematic or description such are: Bus, Star, Ring, Mesh
- Specify the main features of 802.2(Logical Link Control), 802.3(Ethernet), 802.5(Token Ring), 802.11(Wireless) and FDDI (Fiber Distributed Data Interface).
- Network Technologies including Speed, Access Method (CSMA/CA) (Carrier Sense Multiple Access/Collision Avoidance). Fiber Optic Specification, Red Hat Linux 7, VmWare.
- Specify hardware and software solutions for Division users.
- Install components; analyze problems; diagnose and repair systems.
- Oversee technician and consultant as needed.

### Personal Data

Current Address: Date of Birth: Civil Status: Nationality: Email Address: Passport No.:

Mobile No.: 09972332187 Known Language:

Religion:

219 Pagkasilasa Drive Talon-Talon Zamboanga City Philippines June 18, 1973

Married

Filipino

bournemjn@gmail.com

P4483984B Valid Until 21 Jan 2030.

Date issued: 22 Jan 2020. DFA Zamboanga English, Arabic, & Tagalog, Chavacano

Islam

bournemjn@gmail.com 4